Jamie Irwin

Brantford, Ontario

Phone: (519) 771-6779 | Email: jamiejirwin@icloud.com

Technical Documentation ~ Customer & Client Support ~ Cross-Functional Collaboration

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS & KEY COMPETENCIES

Strategic IT Analyst with expertise in optimizing technology to drive business success. Excel in troubleshooting and conducting root-cause analyses and have a strong understanding of various systems. Implements effective solutions while remaining committed to delivering secure, reliable, and user-friendly applications. My focus is on aligning these solutions with business objectives to support internal and external customers.

SOFTWARE, TOOLS & TECHNOLOGY SKILLS

- Networking: TCP/IP, LAN/WAN, VPN, DNS, DHCP, Firewalls, Cisco, Fortinet, Ubiquiti.
- Programming: HTML, CSS, Shell Scripting, PowerShell, Python, JavaScript.
- Systems: Windows Server, Linux, MacOS, AD, Group Policy, VMware, Hyper-V, SCCM.
- Cloud Technologies: AWS, Azure, Google Cloud, SaaS, IaaS, PaaS, Cloud Security.
- Cybersecurity: Threat Analysis, Endpoint Security, Vulnerability Management.
- **Databases**: SQL Server, Database Administration.
- Version Control: GitHub.
- **Testing**: Unit Testing, Integration Testing, QA.
- Data: Data Analysis, Big Data. Automation: Scripting.
- Hardware: Troubleshooting, Repair, Hardware Upgrades, Device Management.
- Emerging Technologies: Artificial Intelligence (AI), Machine Learning (ML), IoT.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cyber Solutions IT

OWNER

- Fortinet System Implementation: Designed and executed a full Fortinet security system installation from the ground up. This included site assessment, equipment ordering, comprehensive wiring and framework setup, customized configuration, testing, and deployment.
- **Infrastructure Standardization**: Streamlined IT infrastructure and standardized network access for a 35-person workforce, ensuring efficient access for daily operations.
- Network Management and Content Filtering: Configured network filters to restrict social media access during work hours for improved productivity.
- **Ubiquiti System Installation**: Established a robust Ubiquiti network setup, including configuring cameras, DVRs, TVs, and network infrastructure to meet the client's surveillance.

Apotex, Brantford

December 2022 to January 2024

IT ANALYST

- Performed daily backups using Acronis, and restarted services on legacy systems running older Server SW. Performed O365 installations and managed licensing as needed by end users.
- Implemented Cisco Video Conferencing throughout the plant and coordinated with vendors and onsite maintenance staff. Negotiated price reductions and provided training to management staff.
- Performed data integrity testing backups of critical files in GMP and non-GMP environments; systems were regularly tested and verified with 100% proof of data recovery matching HASH.
- Implemented Scan to One Drive with Ricoh hardware. Met with vendors and personnel to test and optimize the system before plant-wide deployment.
- Maintained a 93% SLA status with the incoming ticketing system (target 90%). Coordinated with the IT Team from Toronto on hardware and software issues and updated procedures and policies.

PROJECT MANAGER

- Installed 250 IMAX live systems around the globe and coordinated logistics and installations.
- Led Engineers, Technicians, Managers, Manufacturing, theatre staff, and contractors.
- Updated technical documents, scope of work procedures, and balanced budgets to stay within guidelines for IMAX Live theatre rollouts. Developed spreadsheets to capture the process and its entirety while providing continuous improvements.

1Source Metrology, Cambridge

February 2019 to March 2020

DATA MANAGEMENT SPECIALIST

- Installed STARRETT Vision systems and provided onsite training and programming based on customer needs as they varied to a company's specifications; all were successful, which provided stellar customer satisfaction for all involved.
- Arranged onsite visits and provided demos of measuring equipment at manufacturing plants.
- Collaborated with ProLink to develop drivers for new equipment to capture and analyze data.
- Installed and set up SQL servers with IT teams to optimize data capture for production and quality control to provide data analysis via reports to optimize production by reducing costs.

Avaropoint, Brantford

June 2018 to January 2019

IT ANALYST

- Performed customer requirements for a 24-hour support centre for small to medium businesses.
- Configured EUs using Google Admin Console and Windows Server AD, group policy, and backup solutions based on client's needs and budgets, which ranged in size from 2-3 people operations to plants with 150-200 end users.
- Implemented GMAIL via Admin Console and setup G-Drive for commercial end users and backup solutions. Implemented or converted to Office 365, set up email, and trained EUs.

City of Stratford, Stratford

December 2015 to January 2017

SOFTWARE SUPPORT SPECIALIST

- Supported 200 EUs on issues across multiple departments and locations throughout Stratford.
- Updated webpages and supported various projects such as networking infrastructure and VLANs. Deployed software in every department, trained users and created work instructions.
- Travelled to arenas, recreation centres, airports, transit, and city halls to support staff, investigated issues, and maintained the ticketing system and documentation for continuous improvements in all areas.

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

- Service Technician, Prima Power, Chicago, IL, Contract, Jan 2022 May 2022
- Computer Technician, Administration Building, Haldimand County, Contract, Apr 2018 Jul 2018
- IT Helpdesk, Burlington Hydro, Burlington, Contract, Sept 2017 Jan 2018
- Technical Services Specialist, IMAX Corporation, Oakville, May 2008 Jan 2013
- CMM Programmer, Modatek, Progressive Moulded Products and Ultratech Tool & Gauge, September 2004 to May 2008

EDUCATION

- Cyber Security Certificate, ICS2 Accredited College, Hamilton, ON 2023
- Computer Networking Technician Diploma, Mohawk College, Hamilton, ON 2015
- Electronics Technician Diploma, International Correspondence School, Montreal, OC 1997